<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on PoliCICS</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on PoliCICS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://policics.github.io/en/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LEM</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/lem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/en/research/lem/</guid><description>About LEM The Mobile Experimental Laboratory (LEM) is a collaborative space belonging to the Research Center in Social Complexity (CICS) at Universidad del Desarrollo, in Chile. Its mission is to provide a dynamic and flexible environment for conducting innovative research addressing complex social challenges. In this laboratory, students, postdocs, academics, and national and international collaborators linked to CICS gather to work on interdisciplinary projects, all with a common focus: the use of experimental methods in social sciences.</description></item><item><title>Opportunities</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/opportunities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/en/research/opportunities/</guid><description>Our laboratory is constantly looking for talent and support staff for data collection. We also keep open the possibility of future calls for post-doctoral positions.
For those wishing to join as PhD students, the process requires applying to the Doctorate in Social Complexity Sciences (DCCS), a program attached to the Research Center in Social Complexity (CICS).
We invite you to visit our Instagram page to stay informed about the latest news and activities of CICS.</description></item><item><title>Session Log</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/session-log/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/en/research/session-log/</guid><description>The PoliCICS working group maintains an active calendar of regular sessions, traditionally held on Thursdays at 11:30 AM. These instances constitute a fundamental space for discussing research progress, piloting experimental designs, and presenting work by both our researchers and national and international guests. Below you can see the record of the sessions held during the 2025 academic cycle.
Date Presenter Title Abstract April 10 Denise Laroze (CICS) Multi-level collective action in small-scale fisheries: An experimental approach This study investigates the dynamics of collective action in small-scale fisheries through a framed lab-in-the-field experiment with artisanal fishers.</description></item></channel></rss>