<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Networks on PoliCICS</title><link>https://policics.github.io/tags/social-networks/</link><description>Recent content in Social Networks on PoliCICS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://policics.github.io/tags/social-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disadoption Exposure as a New Indicator of Social Contagion in Networks</title><link>https://policics.github.io/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</guid><description>This project extends foundational research on the diffusion of innovations by re-examining the celebrated Korean Family Planning (KFP) dataset. Beyond the initial adoption of modern contraceptives, this work investigates the social dynamics of disadoption, understood as the decision to cease using a modern method. The work is being developed by Aníbal Olivera in collaboration with Thomas Valente, a world reference in the study of networks and health.
The analysis was carried out in three main stages to ensure rigor and build upon established findings.</description></item><item><title>DCCS students participate in major international social networks conference in Paris</title><link>https://policics.github.io/news/estudiantes-dccs-sunbelt-paris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/news/estudiantes-dccs-sunbelt-paris/</guid><description>Sunbelt is the main international congress on social network analysis, and its 2025 edition gathered experts from more than 50 countries around the latest advances and applications of this discipline.
Adolfo Fuentes and Aníbal Olivera, students of the Doctorate in Social Complexity Sciences of the Faculty of Government UDD, participated in the conference Sunbelt 2025 – International Conference on Social Networks, the main global meeting on social network analysis, organized by the International Network for Social Network Analysis (INSNA).</description></item><item><title>DCCS students participate in major international social networks conference in Paris</title><link>https://policics.github.io/research/events/estudiantes-dccs-sunbelt-paris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/research/events/estudiantes-dccs-sunbelt-paris/</guid><description>Sunbelt is the main international congress on social network analysis, and its 2025 edition gathered experts from more than 50 countries around the latest advances and applications of this discipline.
Adolfo Fuentes and Aníbal Olivera, students of the Doctorate in Social Complexity Sciences of the Faculty of Government UDD, participated in the conference Sunbelt 2025 – International Conference on Social Networks, the main global meeting on social network analysis, organized by the International Network for Social Network Analysis (INSNA).</description></item></channel></rss>