<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Current Projects on PoliCICS</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Current Projects on PoliCICS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deputies Dataset 2002-2026</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/deputies-dataset/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/deputies-dataset/</guid><description>This dataset provides ideological position estimates for members of the Chilean Chamber of Deputies across six consecutive legislative periods, spanning from 2002 to 2026 in four-year intervals. The estimates are based exclusively on roll-call votes related to bill proposals debated and voted on in the plenary sessions. It excludes other types of votes, such as those on non-binding agreements or investigative commissions, which do not directly contribute to lawmaking.
Methodology To estimate ideological positions, the dataset includes results from three distinct methods:</description></item><item><title>Disadoption Exposure as a New Indicator of Social Contagion in Networks</title><link>https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/en/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</guid><description>This project extends foundational research on the diffusion of innovations by re-examining the celebrated Korean Family Planning (KFP) dataset. Beyond the initial adoption of modern contraceptives, this work investigates the social dynamics of disadoption, understood as the decision to cease using a modern method. The work is being developed by Aníbal Olivera in collaboration with Thomas Valente, a world reference in the study of networks and health.
The analysis was carried out in three main stages to ensure rigor and build upon established findings.</description></item></channel></rss>