<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on PoliCICS</title><link>https://policics.github.io/categories/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on PoliCICS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://policics.github.io/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disadoption Exposure as a New Indicator of Social Contagion in Networks</title><link>https://policics.github.io/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/research/projects/kfp-disadoption/</guid><description>This project extends foundational research on the diffusion of innovations by re-examining the celebrated Korean Family Planning (KFP) dataset. Beyond the initial adoption of modern contraceptives, this work investigates the social dynamics of disadoption, understood as the decision to cease using a modern method. The work is being developed by Aníbal Olivera in collaboration with Thomas Valente, a world reference in the study of networks and health.
The analysis was carried out in three main stages to ensure rigor and build upon established findings.</description></item><item><title>Session Log</title><link>https://policics.github.io/research/session-log/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/research/session-log/</guid><description>The PoliCICS working group maintains an active calendar of regular sessions, traditionally held on Thursdays at 11:30 AM. These instances constitute a fundamental space for discussing research progress, piloting experimental designs, and presenting work by both our researchers and national and international guests. Below you can see the record of the sessions held during the 2025 academic cycle.
Date Presenter Title Abstract April 10 Denise Laroze (CICS) Multi-level collective action in small-scale fisheries: An experimental approach This study investigates the dynamics of collective action in small-scale fisheries through a framed lab-in-the-field experiment with artisanal fishers.</description></item><item><title>Launch of Deputies Dataset 2002-2026</title><link>https://policics.github.io/news/launch-deputies-dataset/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/news/launch-deputies-dataset/</guid><description>The PoliCICS laboratory is pleased to announce the launch of the Deputies Dataset 2002-2026, a new public resource developed by researcher Jorge Fábrega. This dataset provides systematic estimates of the ideological positions of all members of the Chilean Chamber of Deputies across six consecutive legislative periods.
The estimates are based exclusively on roll-call votes related to bill proposals debated and voted on in plenary sessions, offering a robust tool for legislative analysis.</description></item><item><title>FullCICS Session: Unpacking the Unpredictable with Bastián González Bustamante</title><link>https://policics.github.io/news/fullcics-bastian-gonzalez/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://policics.github.io/news/fullcics-bastian-gonzalez/</guid><description>On October 9th we will have a FullCICS discussion session open to the entire community, organized by PoliCICS. On this occasion, we will have an international guest from Leiden University. Bastián González Bustamante will present his work ‘Unpacking the Unpredictable: From Machine Learning to Generative AI for Detecting Crises in Presidential Democracies’, hosted at OBPEX: https://obpex.com/enlace-udp.
Here are the details of the presentation:
“The study expands on the data collection from my PhD at the University of Oxford (methodological article: https://doi.</description></item></channel></rss>